Prithvi Badipuram

Mumbai | India

8928262992 | 🗷 badipuramprithvi07@gmail.com | 🖸 https://github.com/PRITHVIBADIPURAM | 🗖 https://www.linkedin.com/in/prithvi-badipuram-/

Personal Profile

Resourceful team player with experience in trending data analysis tools and proficiency in leveraging social media platforms. Well-versed in web development and strategies for successfully modernizing workplaces. Possesses a proactive and highly organized approach, demonstrating punctuality and a willingness to tackle any task to support the team. Brings extensive knowledge of research and analysis skills to deliver accurate and insightful outcomes.

Education

Xavier Institute of Engineering - Mumbai, Maharashtra

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

May 2020 - June 2024

SIES COLLEGE OF ARTS, SCIENCE & COMMERCE- Mumbai, Maharashtra

April 2018 - June 2020

H.S.C SCIENCE

The Andhra Education Society's High School

S.S.C SCIENCE April 2017 - June 2018

Skills ____

Programming: Python (Pandas, NumPy), C/C++, Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript (React), SQL.

Tools: Tableau, Microsoft Office, Excel, WordPress, GitHub.

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Problem-solving, Strategic Planning, Communication, Documentation, and Engaging Presentation.

Languages: Fluent (Reading, Writing & Speaking) in English, Hindi, Telugu & Marathi.

Work Experience _____

Strux - Mumbai

Web Developer Intern

July 2022 - February 2023

- Coordinating interdepartmentally to facilitate the completion of company-wide goals through web development.
- Promoted brand Identity by Developing and Delivering an attractive, user-friendly, and unique Website.
- Developed front-end websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, and other editing software.
- Oversaw Technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user problems and satisfy clients' Requirements.
- Applied Emerging Technologies to update and maintain site applicability.

Xavier Institue of Engineering

Committee Member

May 2021 - June 2022

- Gained operational knowledge and supported departmental needs.
- Analyzed problems and worked with teams to develop solutions.

University Projects _

Hair Salon Website / HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Designed and developed a modern website for a hair salon with an intuitive booking system, customer ratings, and global art exposure. Implemented a Progressive Web App (PWA) for enhanced online presence and user experience.

News Website / React.

Built a React news website with real-time updates, offering up-to-date articles and a seamless user experience through API integration.

Sales Analysis / Python.

This project helps to get a detailed report that shows a business's sales performance, as well as customer data and generated revenue

Certifications _____

- Web Developer Intern Strux | June 2023
- Meta Front-End Developer Professional Certificate | June 2023
- Effective Business Communication upGrad | January 2022